<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web building on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/web-building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web building on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 11:35:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/web-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ship PWA Guided by Lighthouse</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/12/03/ship-pwa-guided-by-lighthouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 11:35:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/12/03/ship-pwa-guided-by-lighthouse/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Robert Wiedemann   Nowadays, PWA is so hyped. All the cool kids are implementing PWA, or on the way to implement it. It&amp;rsquo;s like a magic box, they said, what contains ultimate happiness for users. Wow it sounds awesome, right? How is it possible that I could miss this opportunity to stay as a member of the cool kids club?
What is actually PWA? According to Google, Progressive Web Apps are user experiences that have the reach of the web, and are [1]:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 CSS Effect Libraries for Creating Fancy Animations</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/07/11/css-effect-libraries-for-creating-fancy-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 20:57:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/07/11/css-effect-libraries-for-creating-fancy-animations/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Sai Kiran Anagani Vijayawada   Animation is fun. It makes everything look vivid. A good animation is that you won&amp;rsquo;t notice its existence but it pleases your eyes and makes you feel good!
To see fancy animations is really enjoyable, but to make it is not. Specially for me, a CSS -webkit newbie, creating animations with CSS is a dirty job. It needs a lot of guess work and experiments to archive the expect results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo x Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/06/18/hugo-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 15:55:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/06/18/hugo-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>It has been 2 months since I switched from Hexo to Hugo. Everything went smoothly. Until yesterday, I made a small mistake. I messed up my entire blog Git repository, then I have to reconfigure the part of deploying Hugo website to Github Pages&amp;hellip;
To be honest, the initial configuration is simple but I cannot recall it at all. That&amp;rsquo;s why I finally decide to write down this quick note, for the forgetful people, like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hugo Why Not Hexo</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/12/why-hugo-why-not-hexo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 22:47:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/12/why-hugo-why-not-hexo/</guid>
      <description>As you probably remember that I just about switched from jekyll to hexo 2 months ago, now I&amp;rsquo;m again switching from hexo to hugo. Am I crazy? Yep. You want to know why? Let me tell you.
Why hexo was chosen? Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the reasons why I ditched jekyll without any regrets:
 Hexo has a good name Hexo is powered by Node.js Hexo is easy to deploy Hexo supports theme change Hexo is pretty fast  Honestly hexo is quite good and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy living with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hexo Why Not Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/02/26/why-hexo-why-not-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 16:40:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/02/26/why-hexo-why-not-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember several months ago I wrote a post about how to build github.io blog in 3 min? At that time, I was kidding that 3 min in that post title was actually the time to finish reading that post. But today, I could make this raving come true with hexo, a super simple and powerful static blog generator. I switched immediately from jekyll to hexo. Really? Why hexo, why not jekyll anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>