<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLI on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLI on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 14:50:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three jq Tips You May Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/11/03/three-jq-tips-you-may-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 14:50:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/11/03/three-jq-tips-you-may-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>jq is famously known as a powerful command-line JSON parser. Besides performing as a parser, jq has many other handy usages as well. Here, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share 3 jq tips you may need to know.&#xA;JSON Prettier When we curl API to fetch JSON response with raw data. It certainly looks messy:&#xA;$ curl https://api.spacexdata.com/v4/launches/latest {&amp;#34;fairings&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;reused&amp;#34;:false,&amp;#34;recovery_attempt&amp;#34;:true,&amp;#34;recovered&amp;#34;:null,&amp;#34;ships&amp;#34;:[&amp;#34;5ea6ed2e080df4000697c907&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;5ea6ed2e080df4000697c908&amp;#34;]},...&amp;#34;id&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;5ef6a2e70059c33cee4a8293&amp;#34;} Now let&amp;rsquo;s toss raw data into jq and make it look prettier:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Alias -- Did You Git It?</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/07/04/git-alias-did-you-git-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 09:02:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/07/04/git-alias-did-you-git-it/</guid>
      <description>Git alias is powerful and yet simple to set up. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my journey in configuring git alias for my personal use. Now let&amp;rsquo;s dig it and git it!&#xA;Day 1: Why git alias? I was using Tig for some time. It&amp;rsquo;s good but not great. The problems I got during the time:&#xA;It takes time to memorize the default key bindings. Since I&amp;rsquo;m using Colemak keyboard layout, obviously, the default navigation key bindings need to be adjusted accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build A Killer Note-taking System</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:29:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</guid>
      <description>The proverb says, &amp;ldquo;The palest ink is better than the best memory&amp;rdquo;. Note-taking is certainly an essential part of knowledge learning, information collecting and retaining. In the fast-changing digital era, pen, ink and paper may not be able to fulfill the important job of note-taking anymore. So, what&amp;rsquo;s a killer note-taking system nowadays?&#xA;My requirements? My dream system must be Easy, Efficient and Flexible:&#xA;Know where &amp;amp; how to write notes easily without hesitations Find right notes &amp;amp; roll back to old changes efficiently without hassles Convert notes to other formats and share them flexibly without troubles Build it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replace 8 Frequently Used Linux Commands!?</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2018/09/02/replace-8-frequently-used-linux-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:21:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2018/09/02/replace-8-frequently-used-linux-commands/</guid>
      <description>Almost a decade ago, I started to touch the command-line interface (CLI). I&amp;rsquo;m now a nerdy CLI lover and I&amp;rsquo;m so obsessed by its efficiency. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;m always trying out new command-line commands. From time to time, some commands are replaced by other improved ones in my daily workflow. Especially for some frequently used commands, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to find better alternatives.&#xA;Here is a list of improved commands I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
