<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>script on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/script/</link>
    <description>Recent content in script on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 09:02:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/script/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Alias -- Did You Git It?</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/07/04/git-alias-did-you-git-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 09:02:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2020/07/04/git-alias-did-you-git-it/</guid>
      <description>Git alias is powerful and yet simple to set up. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my journey in configuring git alias for my personal use. Now let&amp;rsquo;s dig it and git it!
Day 1: Why git alias? I was using Tig for some time. It&amp;rsquo;s good but not great. The problems I got during the time:
 It takes time to memorize the default key bindings. Since I&amp;rsquo;m using Colemak keyboard layout, obviously, the default navigation key bindings need to be adjusted accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Killer Note-taking System</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:29:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</guid>
      <description>The proverb says, &amp;ldquo;The palest ink is better than the best memory&amp;rdquo;. Note-taking is certainly an essential part of knowledge learning, information collecting and retaining. In the fast-changing digital era, pen, ink and paper may not be able to fulfill the important job of note-taking anymore. So, what&amp;rsquo;s a killer note-taking system nowadays?
My requirements? My dream system must be Easy, Efficient and Flexible:
 Know where &amp;amp; how to write notes easily without hesitations Find right notes &amp;amp; roll back to old changes efficiently without hassles Convert notes to other formats and share them flexibly without troubles  Build it!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>