<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tester on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/tester/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tester on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 22:05:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/tester/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Call Me QA</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/12/please-dont-call-me-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 22:05:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/12/please-dont-call-me-qa/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Gabriel   Before we dive deep into something serious, relax, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a joke first. If it&amp;rsquo;s funny to you, then it&amp;rsquo;s true.
How many QA does it take to change a light bulb? None, we just report the darkness.
&amp;mdash; RoboCoonie™ | Fluffo™ (@RoboCoonie) December 24, 2008  Now let me tell you a truth from the darkness: I don&amp;rsquo;t like people calling me QA, especially those who know me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe as A Photographer, as A Tester</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2018/10/18/observe-as-a-photographer-as-a-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 23:20:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2018/10/18/observe-as-a-photographer-as-a-tester/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Photography is an art of observation. It&amp;rsquo;s about finding something interesting in an ordinary place&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve found it has little to do with the things you see and everything to do with the way you see them.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Elliott Erwitt
 Since the beginning of this year, I took photography as a &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; hobby. The interesting thing I found is that the more I have learned about photography, the more I can feel the similarities between photography and software testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost in the Shell - A Testing Horror Story</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/10/29/ghost-in-the-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 15:11:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/10/29/ghost-in-the-shell/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Scott Walsh   Disclaimer: This story may never happen in my life. However, it may happen in yours.
Rick &amp;ldquo;So, you are Rick? Nice to meet you.&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;m shaking hands with a middle-aged woman in her office. She is talking to me. She is Madame Q, the QA manager of Y Bank.
My name is Rick, 30 years old single male. I&amp;rsquo;m a test automation specialist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking Better Questions for 4 Different Purposes</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/10/03/ask-better-questions-for-four-different-purposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 17:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/10/03/ask-better-questions-for-four-different-purposes/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Jonathan Simcoe    &amp;ldquo;You should not ask questions without knowledge.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; W. Edwards Deming
 A good tester asks good questions. Asking questions is a must-have skill for a software tester. Therefore, as a software tester, I see asking questions as a privilege, which is allowed under any circumstances. However, asking questions is not always easy. We all know sometimes a bad question may cause some communication troubles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m A Tester &amp; I&#39;m A Rubber Duck</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/06/20/i-am-a-rubber-duck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 21:28:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/06/20/i-am-a-rubber-duck/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Silvia Maggi    &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for you, like I&amp;rsquo;ve been there before; I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for you, &amp;lsquo;Cause you&amp;rsquo;re there for me too.&amp;rdquo; [1]
 I&amp;rsquo;m a tester. When a developer talks to me, I see myself as a rubber duck.
A rubber duck? Why not Winnie-the-Pooh, Pikachu or Minion? Because the color doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter 😉 But other things do matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be prepared! Interruption is coming!</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/29/be-prepared-interruption-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 21:25:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/29/be-prepared-interruption-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Mark Hunter    By failing to prepare, you are preparing to fail. - Benjamin Franklin
 Recently I read an interesting article about Why do programmers wear headphones?. The truth is that &amp;ldquo;programmers are easily distracted, headphones eliminate some distractions, thus headphones make programmers.&amp;rdquo; To reduce losing attention by distractions, I could improve my attention span and control the working environment around myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>