<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Qa on Krazy Kevin </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://krazycavin.github.io/tags/qa/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Asks Me Questions but I&#39;ve Some Answers</title>
      <link>http://krazycavin.github.io/2017/01/13/nobody-asks-me-questions-but-i-give-some-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 17:20:53 &#43;0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://krazycavin.github.io/2017/01/13/nobody-asks-me-questions-but-i-give-some-answers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*S4QCcKz1OmopX580Q2X_Vg.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;qa&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far no one asks me any of questions I post below because it&amp;rsquo;s so obvious that I&amp;rsquo;m not interviewed, I&amp;rsquo;m not a speaker, I&amp;rsquo;m not a celebrity in software testing&amp;hellip; But in &lt;strong&gt;edge case&lt;/strong&gt; in the future, there is a little chance that someone would ask me these questions. In this case, the answers are provided even without asking. How awesome it is ¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start these 3 questions from this interview &lt;a href=&#34;https://ukstar.eurostarsoftwaretesting.com/meet-ukstar-speaker-cassandra-leung/&#34;&gt;Meet UKSTAR Speaker – Cassandra Leung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-did-you-get-started-in-software-testing&#34;&gt;How did you get started in software testing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/HVr4gFHYIqeti.gif&#34; alt=&#34;adventure&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say 90% tester has a particular journey to start software testing adventure. I&amp;rsquo;m no exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freshman in Bio-Engineering, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect at all that my profession would be related to software testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start my journey on software testing is a beautiful coincidence I had in my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve a master degree of Biomedical in medical imaging area. As a hobby, I learned some programming skills by myself. Luckily, my diploma and my skills helped me to get an internship in a medical software company. I was in the software department and my mission is to build a web management tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 8 months, the employer was quite happy about the outcomes of my internship. At that moment, they were searching for a new developer who can write scripts to build a in-house test automation framework and writing test cases. Luckily, I was chosen to start my adventure in software testing, as a SDET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-inspires-you&#34;&gt;Who inspires you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/JpMv34oxICQrS.gif&#34; alt=&#34;sylar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by a lot of awesome people. I&amp;rsquo;ve a list of these brilliant people, from whom I would like to steal their brains (I&amp;rsquo;m serious 👿). In software testing, I will name &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/michaelbolton&#34;&gt;Micheal Bolton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lisacrispin&#34;&gt;Lisa Crispin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/testobsessed&#34;&gt;Elisabeth Hendrickson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dnlkntt&#34;&gt;Daniel Knott&lt;/a&gt;. If you know them, please send them my thanks and I&amp;rsquo;m coming for them soon ☺️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-see-for-the-future-of-software-testing&#34;&gt;What do you see for the future of software testing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/8IXEHur.gif&#34; alt=&#34;everyone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it&amp;rsquo;s a difficult question. Although my ability of prediction sucks, I&amp;rsquo;m predicting that the future of software testing is &lt;strong&gt;everyone performs small testing habitually&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional checkpoint style testing will be sliced to some small tiny pieces. They&amp;rsquo;ll be performed continually by every team members in daily development, no matter programmed checking or manual testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone takes care of testing and everyone does it habitually, even not testers. It&amp;rsquo;s a real challenge for the whole team to perform testing habitually, and also a huge challenge for testers to think how to help the whole team to perform testing habitually without testers. As a current trend, testers are shifted around. This movement of testers will bring the seeds of testing knowledge to different people in different job positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-be-continued&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(To be continued&amp;hellip;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
