<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 10:55:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Months With Colemak</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/18/twenty-months-with-colemak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 10:55:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/18/twenty-months-with-colemak/</guid>
      <description>Time truly flies. It has been 20 months since I switched from QWERTY to Colemak keyboard layout. Am I now able to type on the Colemak keyboard as fast as the time flies? Certainly not. My typing speed 20 months ago was 75 WPM on average with QWERTY, now it&amp;rsquo;s 85 WPM on average with Colemak. I can feel the improvement and that&amp;rsquo;s why I never look back to QWERTY again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Killer Note-taking System</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:29:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/04/06/build-a-killer-note-taking-system/</guid>
      <description>The proverb says, &amp;ldquo;The palest ink is better than the best memory&amp;rdquo;. Note-taking is certainly an essential part of knowledge learning, information collecting and retaining. In the fast-changing digital era, pen, ink and paper may not be able to fulfill the important job of note-taking anymore. So, what&amp;rsquo;s a killer note-taking system nowadays?
My requirements? My dream system must be Easy, Efficient and Flexible:
 Know where &amp;amp; how to write notes easily without hesitations Find right notes &amp;amp; roll back to old changes efficiently without hassles Convert notes to other formats and share them flexibly without troubles  Build it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switch to Colemak Keyboard Layout?</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/08/19/why-i-switch-to-colemak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 20:48:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/08/19/why-i-switch-to-colemak/</guid>
      <description>Colemak, pronounced /&amp;lsquo;ko:lmæk/ (Coal-Mac), is a keyboard layout based on QWERTY. It&amp;rsquo;s developed by Shai Coleman and released in 2006. Colemak keyboard layout looks like:
q w f p g j l u y ; a r s t d h n e i o z x c v b k m , . /  What&amp;rsquo;s special about Colemak? Why do I decide to switch from QWERTY to Colemak?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be prepared! Interruption is coming!</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/29/be-prepared-interruption-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 21:25:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2017/04/29/be-prepared-interruption-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Mark Hunter    By failing to prepare, you are preparing to fail. - Benjamin Franklin
 Recently I read an interesting article about Why do programmers wear headphones?. The truth is that &amp;ldquo;programmers are easily distracted, headphones eliminate some distractions, thus headphones make programmers.&amp;rdquo; To reduce losing attention by distractions, I could improve my attention span and control the working environment around myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>