<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-awareness on Kevin Cui</title>
    <link>https://kevcui.github.io/tags/self-awareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-awareness on Kevin Cui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:01:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevcui.github.io/tags/self-awareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Care?</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/09/15/i-do-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:01:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/09/15/i-do-care/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Mitch Lensink   Let&amp;rsquo;s start with your imagination: in a team discussion, someone purposes a solution to solve a certain problem. However, another person expresses a strong opinion against that solution. The discussion is heating up with arguments on two sides back and forth. You are sitting there in your zone silently and listening to the whole conversation insouciantly.
Suddenly, someone asks you, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s your opinion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Quiet</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/27/be-quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:05:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/27/be-quiet/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Jason Rosewell   Nowadays, the Internet becomes an extremely loud and noisy place: endless notifications, messages, chats, posts, streamings, ads, spams, bots&amp;hellip; They are all shouting right in front of you anytime everywhere to catch your limited attention and to steal your precious time.
Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m a part of the problem by generating noisy contents: low-quality jokes, unrealistic complaints, and aggressive arguments&amp;hellip; Once I realized that, the feeling like a commuter in a subway during rush hour: being pushed around forward and backward, I cannot stand still for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Call Me QA</title>
      <link>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/12/please-dont-call-me-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 22:05:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevcui.github.io/2019/07/12/please-dont-call-me-qa/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Gabriel   Before we dive deep into something serious, relax, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a joke:
How many QA does it take to change a light bulb? None, we just report the darkness.
&amp;mdash; RoboCoonie™ | Fluffo™ (@RoboCoonie) December 24, 2008  Funny? True? Now, let me tell you a truth from the darkness: I don&amp;rsquo;t like people calling me QA, especially those who know me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>